Our teacher, Miss Chevalier, was a small woman, with a moon face, plump fingers and curls that sprang straight up from her head, hence the funny name “Poodle”.
我们的老师谢瓦利埃小姐是个身材娇小的女人，圆圆的脸，手指胖乎乎的，一头卷发直直地竖在头上，因此有了“卷毛狗”这个滑稽的外号。
She taught in our reading club.
她在我们的读书俱乐部教课。
Sometimes she would look in and ask what we were reading — not to check but to know.
有时她会进来看看，问我们在读什么——不是为了检查，而是想了解。
That’s what happened the day my club was reading aloud a poem by Henry Longfellow.
我们俱乐部朗读亨利·朗费罗的一首诗那天，就发生了这样的事。
I guess I was better than the others, for Miss Chevalier asked a while later, “Addie, I was wondering if you would recite the whole poem to the Saturday evening club.”
我想我读得比其他人好，因为过了一会儿，谢瓦利埃小姐问道：“艾迪，我在想，你愿不愿意在周六晚间俱乐部活动上背诵整首诗。”
She said a famous professor was going to give a lecture about the poet, and a presentation of that poem would be a fresh way to start.
她说，一位著名教授要来做一场关于这位诗人的讲座，而以朗诵那首诗来开场会很新颖。
She asked me to memorize it.
她让我把这首诗背下来。
“But that shouldn’t be a problem for a child of your ability,” she added.
“不过对于像你这样有能力的孩子来说，这应该不成问题，”她补充道。
I’m telling you, my happy feet barely touched the ground all the way home.
说真的，回家的一路上，我高兴得脚都快不沾地了。
To me, that was the biggest thing ever and I soon learned the whole poem by heart, well prepared for our first rehearsal.
对我来说，那是我经历过的最了不起的事。我很快就把整首诗背得滚瓜烂熟，为第一次排练做好了充分准备。
I was desperately nervous when I went to her office the next day.
第二天去她办公室时，我紧张得要命。
But the good thing was she always had the smile that would make you feel like you just did something right.
不过好在她总是带着那种微笑，让你觉得自己好像刚做对了什么事。
Halfway through the poem, Miss Chevalier stopped me and asked if I knew what “impetuous” meant.
诗背到一半时，谢瓦利埃小姐打断了我，问我知不知道“impetuous”是什么意思。
Despite her encouraging smile, I wanted to sink through the floor because I was unsure about its pronunciation as well as its meaning.
尽管她带着鼓励的微笑，我还是恨不得找个地缝钻进去，因为这个词的读音和意思我都没有把握。
Miss Chevalier pretended not to have noticed my red face and handed me a dictionary, asking me to read the word’s definition aloud.
谢瓦利埃小姐假装没注意到我涨红的脸，递给我一本词典，让我把这个词的释义大声读出来。
“Impetuous has two definitions: rushing with great force or violence; acting suddenly, with little thought.”
“impetuous有两个释义：一是以巨大的力量或猛烈之势向前冲；二是行事突然，几乎不加思考。”
She asked me which one fitted the poem.
她问我哪一个释义符合诗中的意思。
I read both definitions over again, trying to figure it out, but Miss Chevalier must have read my mind.
我把两个释义又读了一遍，想弄明白，但谢瓦利埃小姐一定是看出了我的心思。
“There is no wrong answer,” she said.
“怎么回答都不算错，”她说。
“I want to know your opinion, Addie.”
“我想知道你的看法，艾迪。”
Hesitantly, I said, “Maybe… both.”
我犹豫地说：“也许……两个都是。”
She liked that.
她喜欢这个回答。
“One has to be impetuous both ways or one wouldn’t dare to face up to any challenge.
“一个人得在两种意义上都‘冲动’才行，否则就不敢直面任何挑战。
Would you call yourself impetuous?”
你会说自己是个冲动的人吗？”
I knew she was asking for an opinion.
我知道她是在征求我的看法。
“My mother thinks it is improper for girls to be impetuous, anyway.”
“反正我妈妈认为女孩子冲动是不得体的。”
She said my mom was somewhat right about that.
她说我妈妈在这一点上有几分道理。
“But girls should also be wise enough to take up challenges when needed.
“但女孩子也应该足够明智，在需要时接受挑战。
I believe you are such a girl.”
我相信你就是这样的女孩。”
After that, I would never call Miss Chevalier “Poodle” again.
从那以后，我再也不叫谢瓦利埃小姐“卷毛狗”了。